Finding Aid for the George Schaefer Papers LSC.0588
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 4: Miscellaneous, 1957-1991; 3 boxes
  - Subseries 4B: Production materials, 1961-1976
    - Paramount Pictures., 5 items. (Box 60, Folder 3)
      General correspondence and signed agreement.
    - Showbills (folder 1 of 2)., ca. 30 items. (Box 60, Folder 4)
      8 x 10 negatives of Broadway showbills, possibly used for researching publicity and marketing.
    - Showbills (folder 2 of 2)., 27 items. (Box 60, Folder 5)
      Prints of the showbill negatives, with annotations.
    - Stanford, Donald Kent., ca. 25 items. (Box 60, Folder 6)
      correspondence.
    - Zukor, Adolph (Paramount Pictures)., 11 items. (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 4C: UCLA, 1970-1991
    Assorted class materials and play excerpts. Arranged alphabetically by subject of the file contents.
    - Class materials., 5 items. (Box 61, Folder 1)
      William Hurt's response to a UCLA student question at the Spencer Tracy Award 1988; 410A Film Pre-Production syllabus winter 1991; 2nd year MFA list; "Elia Kazan: On What Makes a Director"; script for Dennis Potter's Son of a Man.
    - Untitled play., 1 item. (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - The College Widow., 1 item. (Box 61, Folder 2)
      Photocopy of a play by George Ade.
    - An Enemy of the People., 7 items. (Box 61, Folder 3)
      Includes excerpt and handwritten Ibsen outline (inserted at page 196).
    - The Good Fairy., 1 item. (Box 61, Folder 4)
      Photocopy of a play by Ferenc Molnar, translated and adapted by Jane Hinton.
    - Jitta's Atonement., 1 item. (Box 61, Folder 5)
      Photocopy of a play by Siegfried Trebitsch.
    - Make a Wish., 3 items. (Box 61, Folder 6)
      Photocopy from 1951 playbill, correspondence, Suits Me Fine by Preston Sturgis, copyright research report for Make a Wish(adaptation of The Good Fairy).
    - Play excerpts., 3 items. (Box 61, Folder 7)
      From Blithe Spirit, The Voice of the Turtle, Before Breakfast.
    - Theatre Class 138., 15 items. (Box 61, Folder 8)
      Annotated scenes from The Wild Duck, Hedda Gabler, A Doll's House, Ghosts, Man and Superman, Saint Joan, The Devil's Disciple, Pygmalion, Captain Brassbound's Conversion, The Glass Menagerie, Streetcar Named Desire, Cat on a Hot Tin Roof, and others.
- Series 5: Television, 1959-1989; 11 boxes
  Production files and a scrapbook related to George Schaefer's work in television. Arranged in two subseries:
  5A. Production files, 1959-19898 (10 boxes).
  5B. Scrapbook, 1967 (1 box).
  - Subseries 5A. Production files, 1959-1989
    - Amelia Earhart--Script., 1 item. (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Blind Ambition--Clippings (folder 1 of 2)., ca. 25 items. (Box 62, Folder 2)
      Newspaper.
    - Blind Ambition--Clippings (folder 2 of 2)., ca. 75 items. (Box 62, Folder 3)
      Photocopies.
    - Blind Ambition--Legal and financial file., 38 items. (Box 62, Folder 4)
      Correspondence, signed agreements, statements, invoices.
    - Blind Ambition--Photographs., 60 items. (Box 62, Folder 5)
      Research photos from Laura Lee Grubich.
    - Blind Ambition--Production and publicity., ca. 30 items. (Box 62, Folder 6)
      Ratings information, map, clippings, photocopies of additional research photographs, and assorted print materials.
    - Blind Ambition--Script, Part 1., 1 item. (Box 62, Folder 7)
      Annotated with supporting production materials.
    - Blind Ambition--Script, Part 2., 1 item. (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Blind Ambition--Script, Part 3., 1 item. (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Blind Ambition--Script, Part 4., 1 item. (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - The Bunker--Legal and financial file., ca. 25 items. (Box 63, Folder 4)
      Correspondence, invoices, statements.
    - The Bunker--Script (folder 1 of 2)., 1 item. (Box 63, Folder 5)
      One edited script, labeled "Adie's."
    - The Deadly Game--Script (folder 2 of 2)., 1 item. (Box 63, Folder 6)
      With annotations.
    - Do Not Go Gentle Into That Good Night--Casting., ca. 25 items. (Box 63, Folder 7)
      Correspondence and cast list.
    - Do Not Go Gentle Into That Good Night--Correspondence (folder 1 of 2)., ca. 100 items. (Box 64, Folder 1)
      Regarding production, legal and financial issues.
    - Do Not Go Gentle Into That Good Night--Correspondence (folder 2 of 2)., ca. 100 items. (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Do Not Go Gentle Into That Good Night--Legal and financial file., ca. 60 items. (Box 64, Folder 3)
      Correspondence, contracts, payroll, figures.
    - Do Not Go Gentle Into That Good Night--Production and format., ca. 50 items. (Box 64, Folder 4)
      Set diagram, set blueprint, and assorted printed materials.
    - Do Not Go Gentle Into That Good Night--Publicity., ca. 50 items. (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Do Not Go Gentle Into That Good Night--Script (folder 1 of 2)., 1 item. (Box 64, Folder 6)
      Entitled "The Odyssey of Peter Schermann."
    - Do Not Go Gentle Into That Good Night--Script (folder 2 of 2)., 1 item. (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - F. Scott Fitzgerald and The Last of the Belles--Production., ca 30 items. (Box 65, Folder 2)
      Correspondence, signed contract, cast list, clippings.
    - F. Scott Fitzgerald and The Last of the Belles--Script., 1 item. (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - First You Cry--Production., ca. 30 items. (Box 65, Folder 4)
      Correspondence, daily production reports, staff and crew list, rehearsal schedule, signed contract, still, clippings.
    - First You Cry--Script., 2 items. (Box 65, Folder 5)
      First draft annotated, with shooting schedule.
    - The Girl Called Hatter Fox--Production., 13 items. (Box 65, Folder 6)
      Financial file, signed contract, clippings.
    - The Girl Called Hatter Fox--Script., 2 items. (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - The Hands of Danofrio--Production., 9 items. (Box 65, Folder 8)
      Also known as "The Gallery."
    - The Hands of Danofrio--Revue Studios., 11 items. (Box 65, Folder 9)
      Signed contracts/agreements.
    - Here There Be Dragons--Production., 16 items. (Box 66, Folder 1)
      Correspondence, cast list, clippings. See also box 79 for 1 cassette marked "Sampler-Sheldon Harnick."
    - Here There Be Dragons--Script., 2 items. (Box 66, Folder 2)
      With annotations. Full title: Here There Be Dragons: The Voyage of the Mayflower.
    - Here There Be Dragons--Revue Studios., 8 items. (Box 66, Folder 3)
      Signed contracts/agreements and correspondence.
    - In This House of Brede--Publicity., 4 items. (Box 66, Folder 4)
      Fan mail, press releases, clippings.
    - In This House of Brede--Script., 1 item. (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Land of Hope--Production file., 14 items. (Box 66, Folder 6)
      Correspondence, clippings, 3 set design blueprints, annotated script.
    - The Last of Mrs. Lincoln--Correspondence., ca. 75 items. (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - The Last of Mrs. Lincoln--Production and publicity., ca. 30 items. (Box 66, Folder 8)
      Press releases, clippings, and assorted print materials.
    - The Last of Mrs. Lincoln--Script., 2 items. (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Love Story--Correspondence., ca. 50 items. (Box 67, Folder 2)
      Fan mail and letters from NBC and Paramount.
    - Love Story--Episode entitled "Beginner's Luck.", 20 items. (Box 67, Folder 3)
      Correspondence, production, publicity, 1 still, and script (annotated first draft).
    - Love Story--Episode entitled "The Youngest Lovers.", ca. 40 items. (Box 67, Folder 4)
      Correspondence, production, publicity, and 2 scripts (1 annotated shooting script).
    - Love Story--Production and publicity., ca. 25 items. (Box 67, Folder 5)
      Staff and crew list, NBC format, press releases, clippings, and assorted printed materials.
    - My Father and My Mother--Correspondence., ca. 50 items. (Box 67, Folder 6)
      Letters from CBS, AFTRA, Robert Crean, Kennedy Child Study Center.
    - My Father and My Mother--Production and format., ca. 60 items. (Box 67, Folder 7)
      Rehearsal and production schedules, payroll, figures, billing, and assorted print materials. See Also box 79 for prints: 2 35mm color prints with invoice and correspondence; 1 D.P. answer print promo from Reeves Sound Studio.
    - My Father and My Mother--Publicity., ca. 25 items. (Box 68, Folder 1)
      Press release, clippings, and assorted print materials.
    - My Father and My Mother--Script., 1 item. (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Our Town--Production., ca. 25 items. (Box 68, Folder 3)
      Correspondence, press releases, clippings.
    - Our Town--Script., 3 items. (Box 68, Folder 4)
      With annotations and supporting production materials.
    - People vs. Jean Harris--Production., 17 items. (Box 68, Folder 5)
      Contact list, credits, signed agreement, press release, clippings.
    - People vs. Jean Harris--Script, Part 1., 7 items. (Box 68, Folder 6)
      With annotation.
    - People vs. Jean Harris--Script, Part 2., 4 items. (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - A Piano for Mrs. Cimino--Contract., 1 item. (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - A Piano for Mrs. Cimino--Script., 1 item. (Box 69, Folder 1)
      Revised draft annotated.
    - Sandburg's Lincoln--Clippings., ca. 25 items. (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Sandburg's Lincoln--Floor plans (folder 1 of 3)., 10 items. (Box 69, Folder 3)
      Set diagrams, sketches. See also box 77 for 2 oversized floor plans.
    - Sandburg's Lincoln--Floor plans (folder 2 of 3)., 17 items. (Box 69, Folder 4)
      Set diagrams, sketches.
    - Sandburg's Lincoln--Floor plans (folder 3 of 3)., 18 items. (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Sandburg's Lincoln--Legal and financial file (folder 1 of 2)., ca. 80 items. (Box 69, Folder 6)
      Correspondence, statements, distribution reports, production reports, signed agreements, and assorted printed materials.
    - Sandburg's Lincoln--Legal and financial file (folder 2 of 2)., 13 items. (Box 70, Folder 1)
      Contracts and correspondence.
    - Turn the Key Deftly--Key sheets., 18 items. (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Turn the Key Deftly--Production., 15 items. (Box 70, Folder 11)
      6 sketches and assorted printed materials.
    - Sandburg's Lincoln--Photographs (folder 1 of 2)., 18 items. (Box 70, Folder 2)
      13 stills (1 with duplicates), 1 polaroid, 1 photograph of Lincoln (with 2 duplicates), correspondence.
    - Sandburg's Lincoln--Photographs (folder 2 of 2)., 21 items. (Box 70, Folder 3)
      19 color postcard photos of locations, 1 black and white photo.
    - Sandburg's Lincoln--Publicity., ca. 60 items. (Box 70, Folder 4)
      Correspondence, press releases, clippings, and assorted print materials.
    - Sandburg's Lincoln--Scripts (folder 1 of 4)., 2 items. (Box 70, Folder 5)
      With annotations. Episodes "The Politician" and "Within Sight of Canaan."
    - Sandburg's Lincoln--Scripts (folder 2 of 4)., 2 items. (Box 70, Folder 6)
      With annotations. Episodes "Mrs. Lincoln's Husband" and "Prairie Lawyer."
    - Sandburg's Lincoln--Scripts (folder 3 of 4)., 1 item. (Box 70, Folder 7)
      With annotations. Episode "The Unwilling Warrior."
    - Sandburg's Lincoln--Scripts (folder 4 of 4)., 2 items. (Box 70, Folder 8)
      With annotations. Episodes "Crossing Fox River" and "The Last Days."
    - Turn the Key Deftly--Correspondence., 18 items. (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Turn the Key Deftly--Script., 3 items. (Box 71, Folder 1)
      Final draft.
    - A War of Children--Publicity and production., 32 items. (Box 71, Folder 10)
      Clippings and assorted printed materials.
    - USA--Production., 60 items. (Box 71, Folder 2)
      Correspondence, 22 key sheets, clippings, and assorted printed materials.
    - USA--Script (folder 1 of 2)., 1 item. (Box 71, Folder 3)
      As taped.
    - USA--Script (folder 2 of 2)., 1 item. (Box 71, Folder 4)
      Before taping.
    - Vidocq and Younger Generation--Revue Studios' contracts., 8 items. (Box 71, Folder 5)
      Never made.
    - Who'll Save Our Children?--Correspondence and contract., 15 items. (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Who'll Save Our Children?--Script., 1 item. (Box 71, Folder 7)
      Also known as "The Orchard Children."
    - A War of Children--Correspondence (folder 1 of 2)., ca. 100 items. (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - A War of Children--Correspondence (folder 2 of 2)., ca. 25 items. (Box 71, Folder 9)
      Congratulatory correspondence on the Emmy award.
  - Subseries 5B. Scrapbook, 1966-1968
    - CBS Playhouse., 1 item. (Box 72)
      Clippings related to the CBS Playhouse productions, including Do Not Go Gentle Into That Good Night.
- Series 6: Theatre, 1961-1987; 4 boxes
  Production files and a scrapbook related to George Schaefer's work in theatre. Arranged in two subseries:
  6A. Production files, 1961-1987 (3 boxes).
  6B. Scrapbook, 1961-1963 (1 box).
  - Subseries 6A: Production files, 1961-1987
    - Another Part of the Forest--Production file., ca. 60 items. (Box 73, Folder 1)
      Correspondence, clippings, 4 set design plans.
    - Mixed Couples--Script (2 of 2)., 1 item. (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - On Golden Pond--Production file., 4 items. (Box 73, Folder 11)
      Sketches, clipping, theatre publicity.
    - The Great Indoors--Production file., 17 items. (Box 73, Folder 2)
      Correspondence, production materials, playbill, press releases, clippings.
    - Leave it to Jane--Script (folder 1 of 2)., 1 item. (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Leave it to Jane--Script (folder 2 of 2)., 1 item. (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Leave it to Jane and The Boys from Syracuse--Casting., 47 items. (Box 73, Folder 5)
      Headshots (photocopies), callback lists, contact and audition information.
    - Leave it to Jane and The Boys from Syracuse--Clippings., ca. 50 items. (Box 73, Folder 6)
      Reviews (photocopies).
    - Lyndon--Script., 1 item. (Box 73, Folder 7)
      Final draft annotated.
    - Mixed Couples--Production file., ca. 30 items. (Box 73, Folder 8)
      Correpondence, invoices, cast information, publicity, clippings, stagebill.
    - Mixed Couples--Script (folder 1 of 2)., 1 item. (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Slightly Delayed--Production file., 9 items. (Box 74, Folder 1)
      Annotated working script, 5 set design plans, cast information.
    - Write Me a Murder--Clippings., ca. 50 items. (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Write Me a Murder--Correspondence., ca. 60 items. (Box 74, Folder 11)
      Letters from Foote, Cone, and Belding, H.M. Tennent, LTD., and Sol Jacobson.
    - Write Me a Murder--Photographs (folder 1 of 2)., 40 items. (Box 74, Folder 12)
      London production, black and white.
    - The Student Prince--Clippings., ca. 25 items. (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - The Student Prince--Correspondence., ca. 60 items. (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - The Student Prince--Production and publicity., 29 items. (Box 74, Folder 4)
      Playbill, 19 set design blueprints, clippings, and assorted print materials.
    - To Broadway with Love--Correspondence., ca. 30 items. (Box 74, Folder 5)
      Letters from Columbia Records and Morton Da Costa.
    - To Broadway with Love--Legal file., ca. items. (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - To Broadway with Love--Production file., ca. 30 items. (Box 74, Folder 7)
      Sheet music for Boss and Harnick songs, 4 set design blueprints, and assorted printed materials. See also box 78 for 1 LP of the original cast recording. See also box 80 for 2 magnetic sound tapes with narrator-Morton De Costa, piano-Tony Cristofaro, sing.
    - To Broadway with Love--Publicity., 10 items. (Box 74, Folder 8)
      Clippings, poster, and assorted print materials (see oversize folder 81 for flattened poster).
    - To Broadway with Love--Script., 1 item. (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Write Me a Murder--Photographs (2 of 2)., 71 items. (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Write Me a Murder--Production., 2 items. (Box 75, Folder 2)
      Props list and set design blueprint.
    - Write Me a Murder--Publicity., 51 items. (Box 75, Folder 3)
      Playbills, 13 photographs (3 duplicates), negative, press releases, clippings, and assorted printed materials.
    - Write Me a Murder--Scripts., 2 items. (Box 75, Folder 4)
      Annotated and first version entitled "King of the Castle."
    - Zenda--Clippings., ca. 60 items. (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Zenda--Correspondence., ca. 30 items. (Box 75, Folder 6)
      Letters from Ed Lester.
    - Zenda--Production and format., 21 items. (Box 75, Folder 7)
      Script notes, credits, press releases, 3 key sheets, 5 blueprints of set plans, and assorted print materials.
    - Zenda--Publicity., 53 items. (Box 75, Folder 8)
      Playbills, souvenir journal, stills, press releases, correspondence, clippings, and assorted printed materials (see oversize folder 81 for posters).
  - Subseries 6B: Scrapbook, 1961-1963
    - Scrapbook., 1 item. (Box 76)
      Clippings and reviews related to Write Me a Murder, Zenda, and To Broadway with Love.